有人说英雄都是天生的
Some say heroes are born.
还有一些人说英雄都是后天培养的
Others they're made.
可我只知道有一个英雄
I only ever knew one.
名字叫做贝奥武夫
Beowulf.'
驾
Ya!
父亲
Father!
快跑
Run!
呀
Ya!
啊啊啊
Aaaagh!
死亡圣殿将会欢迎他的到来
He will be welcomed in the Halls of the Dead.
我知道
I know.
我是赫罗斯加
I'm Hrothgar.
鹿厅的领主
Thane of Heorot.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
贝奥武夫
Beowulf.
人们会记住你的名字的
The people will remember it.
贝奥武夫
Beowulf?
为什么千里迢迢来到这里去看一个老领主死去
Why come so far to watch an old thane die?
我们分开的时候很不愉快
We parted badly.
我不能就这样放任不管
I wouldn't leave it that way.
重返护盾大陆
第一集
你难道没把尸体埋在护盾大陆吗
Don't you bury your dead in the Shieldlands?
-是一个泥巴种干的  -山怪干的
- A mud-born did this.  - A troll?
咬痕很小还很深
The bite marks are too small and deep.
根本没时间去埋他的尸体
There's no time to bury him.
如果我们还想要在天黑之前赶到鹿厅的话
Not if we're to make Heorot by nightfall.
我真不喜欢这地方
I don't like this place.
好啊 那你就回家啊
Well, then, go home.
面对那帮动私刑的暴民
Face that lynch mob.
他们不是暴民 就是亲密的朋友恰好还是死去那个老人的家人
It wasn't a mob. Just close friends and family of the dead man.
你亲手杀了的那个老伙儿
The dead man you killed.
每个故事都有好坏两个方面
There are two sides to every story.
那你为什么要把我从这帮人手里救出来
Why did you save me from them, anyway?
我们都会犯错
We all make mistakes.
当你说你们分开的时候很不愉快
When you said you parted badly...
现在看看周围 我想知道有多不愉快
from the look of things,I'm wondering how badly?
你那把小刀是不是需要修理一下
Still need that blade of yours fixed?
现在就是很好的时机
Now might be a good time.
-怎么了  -贝奥武夫
- What is it?  - Beowulf.
你知道我们不能让你进去的
You know we can't let you enter.
你二十年前动作就不麻利
You were slow 20 years ago.
你现在只能会更慢
You'll only be slower now.
你好啊 史林
Hello, Slean.
杀了他
Kill him.
贝奥武夫
Beowulf!
够了
Enough!
史林
Slean.
在我做总管时 我不允许这座大殿被鲜血染红
There'll be no more blood spilt in this hall while I'm Reeve.
他已经被驱逐了
He was banished.
任何人都会犯错
On anyone's orders.
我来见赫罗斯加
I'm here to see Hrothgar.
贝奥武夫
Beowulf!
赫罗斯加已经死了
Hrothgar's dead.
铁匠在哪
Where's the smith?
你现在就看着她呢
You're looking at her.
你是个女孩
You're a girl.
有着一个大铁锤的女孩
With a big hammer.
你觉得你可以用大铁锤修好这个吗
Think you can fix this with that big hammer of yours?
如果你先把钱给我 我就可以
If you pay upfront, I can.
你觉得我配不上这把好刀吗
You don't think I'm good for it?
以你貌取人有问题吗
Does being judged on your appearance trouble you?
今晚的宴会就是为了纪念赫罗斯加
Tonight we feast in Hrothgar's honour.
我可以去看他的遗体吗 向他道别
May I see the body? To say farewell.
史林 不管我们之间发生过什么都已经过去了
Slean, whatever else has passed between us...
这不是我儿子就可以决定的
That is not my son's decision.
我现在是大领主了
I am Thane.
丽达 人的最后一餐是不可以被他的朋友和家人拒之门外的
Rheda, no family or friend can be turned away from a man's last feast.
你什么都不是
You're neither.
住手 让他留下
No. Let him stay.
我不会让我丈夫的名誉受到玷污 但是你绝不能去见他的遗体
I would not dishonour my husband,but you will not see the body.
丽达 丽达
Rheda? Rheda!
发生什么事了
What is going on?
哥哥
Brother?
你到底要不要介绍我 你这老滑头
Well, are you gonna announce me or not, you old goat?
布莱根的大领主 阿布莱肯
Abrecan, Thane of Bregan.
妹妹
Sister.
或者我现在应该称呼你为鹿厅的大领主了
Or should I address you as Thane of Heorot now?
进来吧
Come.
史林 过来听听你舅舅的新鲜事
Slean, come and hear your uncle's news.
管好你自己 小子
Watch yourself, lad.
-你干的  -那时候他正准备要杀了我呢
- You did this.  - He was trying to kill me at the time.
那你至少帮我给他挪个地方吧
Well, at least help me move him.
其他领主会在葬礼仪式结束后来这里集合
The other thanes arrive for the gathering after the funeral rites.
而且他们都将会赞成你继承赫罗斯加的
And they all vote for you to succeed Hrothgar.
一个大领主必须统治我们所有人 为什么不是你呢
One thane must rule us all. Why not you?
有些人怀疑我父亲继承人的提名
Some doubt my father's nomination as his successor.
还在对你父亲把你忽略了感到隐隐作痛吗 侄子
Still smarting that Hrothgar passed you over, nephew?
如果他们真的怀疑 那他们肯定不会像我这样了解你母亲
If they do, they do not know your mother as I do.
你丈夫做了一个勇敢的决定
It was a bold choice your husband made.
人们迟早都会来的 给他们点时间
People will come round. Give it time.
没有时间了
There is no time.
把他放到这里 帮我个忙
Leave him in there. Give me a hand here.
快点
Quickly.
他的肩膀受伤了
It's his shoulder.
我知道
I know.
-都归你了  -帮我扶着他
- All yours.  - Hold him.
扶紧点 他又不会去亲你
Tightly. He's not gonna kiss you.
-归位会很疼但你会活下来的  -准备好没
- It'll hurt a lot more going back in but you'll live. - Ready?
你和以前的治疗师很不同
You're different to the old healer.
一 二
One, two...
啊
Agh!
-哪点不一样  -更暴力了
- Different how? - More violent?
好吧
Well...
可以走了
Move.
包扎一下他的手 可以吗
Bandage his hand, will you?
-我想我可以来帮忙   -或者是拜仁派你来监视我
- Thought I might help. - Or Bayen sent you to keep an eye on me.
好吧 你确实显得比较异类
Well, you made quite the impression.
-你为什么要留下来参加宴会呢  - 你对我在这吃喝有意见吗
- Why are you staying for the feast?- You begrudge me food and drink?
你们能换个地方来交流了解彼此吗
Would you to mind getting to know each other somewhere else?
就这样么  连句谢谢都没有
That's it? No thanks?
你是他们能在这存活的原因
Well, you are the reason they're here.
说得好
Fair point.
你会参加今天晚上的宴会么
Will you be at the feast tonight?
每个人都要去
Everyone will.
有人已经死了而晚上还要举办宴会
Somebody's died and there's a feast tonight.
我们应该留下来
We should stay.
那是你的老领主
It's your old thane.
我表示同情
My sympathies.
别说虚假的话了
You almost sound like you mean it.
他是个伟大的人
He was a great man.
留下他满腔怒火的儿子
Who left his son full of rage.
最起码丽达是个有智慧的人
At least Rheda is wise.
但是她够强大么
But is she strong?
她有我们
She has us.
我去叫丽达准备一下  你要确保贝奥武夫远离这个屋子
I'll have Rheda ready. You keep Beowulf from this chamber.
这间厅里装满了回忆
This hall is full of memories.
贝奥武夫
Beowulf.
Beowulf?
-没有已婚女子  -嗯嗬
- No married women. - Hm?
爱情是盲目的
Love is blind.
这是我丈夫的守灵夜
My husband's wake.
而我所能做的就是咒骂他委任我成为继承人
And all I can do is curse him for appointing me his successor.
这裙子 是全新的
The dress, it's new.
还有点紧
It's a little tight.
你本可以拒绝他
You could've refused him.
让你儿子成为新领主
Let your son become Thane.
赫罗斯加是对的 史林还没准备好
Hrothgar was right. Slean's not ready.
他们都在等你
They're waiting for you.
你没有必要在今晚就接手赫罗斯加的遗嘱
You don't have to be Hrothgar tonight.
就像新裙子 权利与服饰相匹配
Like a new dress, power fits better with the wearing.
拜托
Please!
你会适应的
You'll become accustomed to it.
甚至可能会很享受它
May even come to enjoy it.
记住 在男人来到护盾大陆前
Remember, before man came to the Shieldlands,
在这唯一的物种是泥巴种
the only living things here were the mud-born.
巨人们 侏儒们和犬妖
Giants, trolls and the wolf-like barghest.
流淌着黑色血液 从这黑色的泥土里出生
All with black blood, all born from this land's dark dirt.
来吧
Go on.
我记得我干过这事但是记不起来为什么了
I remember doing it but I don't remember why...
哈
Ho!
不要刻意追求尊荣
Don't go seeking after glory.
它会主动来找你
It'll find you.
史林
Slean?
他没有继承王位
He didn't succeed his father.
任命继承者是赫罗斯加的权利
It was Hrothgar's right to name his successor.
他确实一直给人一种恶作剧的感觉
He always did have a sense of mischief.
你不认为一个女人可以掌权
You don't think a woman can rule?
大部分人都是
Many do.
几乎没人相信
Few are seen to.
拜仁 我们想今晚要回我们的酬劳
Bayen, we want our pay tonight.
不 你们要像其他人一样等着  现在让我走
No. You wait like everyone else. Now let go of me.
塔恩
Tarn.
你的总管有点老啊
Your reeve's a little long in the tooth.
赫罗斯加很信赖他
Hrothgar relied on him.
我肯定也一样
And I must, too.
一个寡妇
A widow.
她丈夫六年前死了
Her husband died six summers ago.
她现在自己经营着铁匠铺
She owns the smithy now.
我们的不速之客  弄清他想干什么
Our unwanted guest, find out his intentions.
这是利拉 来自铁匠铺
This is Lila. From the smithy.
我见过你的女儿 很直率的女孩
I met your daughter. Forthright girl.
她这点是遗传我
She gets it from me.
你并不是想买五节铁链 是不
You're not looking to buying five lengths of iron chain, are you?
不是的
Not really, no.
很好
Good.
我来这不是工作的
I didn't come here to work.
手怎么样了
How's the hand?
你不能进入禁地
Y-You can't enter the private quarters.
贝奥武夫 在这没有你的容身之地
Beowulf, you have no place here.
拜仁 我只是想看下赫罗斯加
Bayen. I just want to see Hrothgar.
你已经听见丽达说的了
You heard Rheda.
你当护盾人多少年了
How many years were you a Shieldman?
-30年  -总管当了10年
- 30? - And Reeve for ten.
并不仅仅如此 我帮助他教育他儿子 和你
Not only that, I helped him teach his son, and you,
从一个剑端到另一个  如果你记得的话
one end of a sword from another, if you remember.
我还记得
I do.
所以你明白我们之间是怎样的
So you know how it was between us.
赫罗斯加就像我的父亲
Hrothgar was like a father to me.
你是一个很棒的学生
You were a good learner.
也是一个很棒的剑手
Good sword-hand, too.
史林 你的关节都发白了 不要握的太紧
Slean, your knuckles are white. Don't hold it so tight.
不用你来告诉我怎么做 你以为你是谁
Don't tell me what to do. Who do you think you are?
你过不去的
You'll not pass.
你什么都不是 贝奥武夫
You're nothing, Beowulf.
你父亲也一无是处
Your father was nothing.
住手 现在
Stop it! Now!
你什么都不算 贝奥武夫
'You're nothing, Beowulf.'
我可以杀了你
I could kill you.
你本可以但是你不会
You could but you won't.
你希望是其他人么
Would you rather it was someone else?
-什么  -贝奥武夫
- What? - Beowulf.
-我看见你了 -和他讲话
- I saw you. -Talking to him.
你还没完全拥有我
You don't own me.
我会的
But I would.
你的母亲不会同意的
Your mother would never allow it.
拜仁
Bayen?
如果没有人替我报仇
If I'm not avenged...
我将无法进入死亡圣殿
I'll never enter the Halls of the Dead.
我会替你报仇的  我发誓
I will avenge you. I swear it.
杀人凶手
Murderer.
真的是你杀了他吗
Is it true?
一个泥巴种杀死了拜仁
A mud-born killed Bayen.
现场没有野兽  只有他  他当时站在尸体旁边
There was no beast, only him. He stood over the body.
杀人偿命 这是你极度热爱的法令规定的
Blood for blood, that's what the law you love so much says.
你没有证据  没有目击到 也没有动机
You've no evidence, no witness and no motive.
缺乏任何一个条件 一个人都无法被定罪
Without one of these, a man cannot be condemned.
他有动机
He had motive.
拜仁拒绝了他看一眼赫罗斯加的请求
Bayen turned him away from Hrothgar's body.
-他威胁了拜仁  -威胁
- He threatened him. - Threatened?
那只是老朋友之间开的玩笑
It was banter, between old friends.
当即处决他  干净利落
Do it here, quick and clean.
请您对现在做出决定 而不是对过去
Make your decision on the present, not the past.
以一个领主的身份 而不是以一个母亲的身份
As a thane, not as a mother.
-她根本不是你的母亲  -安静
- She was never your mother! - Be quiet!
你就是个废物贝奥武夫  你父亲也是个废物
You're nothing, Beowulf. Your father was nothing.
-停下 马上  -他差点就杀掉我
- Stop it! Now! - He tried to kill me.
刚才是他无端袭击
It was an unprovoked attack.
贝奥武夫想杀死我儿子
Beowulf tried to kill my son.
我们的儿子
Our son.
他会在老地方被处决
It will be done in the usual place.
不要让任何人看到
Before any who wish to see.
这是我们的规定
That is our law.
-我可以跟你一起出去吗  -今天不行
- Can I come? - Not today.
我要赶很长时间的路 而且我想天黑之前回来
I've a long way to go and I want to be back before dark.
下次吧
Next time.
-噢 我的新女儿  -抱歉你在说什么
- Ah! My new daughter. - I'm sorry?
-你妈妈和我  -你对她做了什么
- Your mother and I  - What did you do to her?
我娶了她 然后和她上床了
Married her, then shared her bed.
那不是你的制服吗
Isn't that your custom?
停下
Stop!
你在想什么啊
What were you thinking?!
我什么也没想啊
I wasn't.
我有预感 他们会杀了你和你的朋友
I had my way, they'd kill you with your friend.
什么
What?
- 爱尔维纳  -别急
- Elvina! - Easy.
-她朝那边走了  -她发生了什么
- She went that way.  - What happened to her?
一个泥巴种 它追着她跑
A mud-born beast, he chased after her.
-在哪 -畜栏那边
- Where?  - Past the corral.
朝着西部丛林的方向
Toward the Western Wood?
带我走
Took your time.
哇哦  稳当点
Whoa! Steady.
快拦住他们
Stop them!
史林 你在做什么
Slean? What do you think you're doing?
如果他接替了赫罗斯加的位置
If he's ever to take Hrothgar's place,
他一定被视作一位战士
he must be seen as a warrior.
-而我不是  - 丽达 我
- As I'm not?  - Rheda, I...
这是事实
It's true.
我也许永远不会手握宝剑或让Huskarl陷入战争
I may never wield a sword or lead the Huskarl into battle.
我永远不会成为赫罗斯加
I'll never be Hrothgar.
但我会统治这片领土
But I will rule.
哇哦 稳下来 稳下来
Whoa! Steady! Steady!
死的犬妖  是野兽杀死的
Dead barghest. Beast killed it.
-野兽在这发现了她  -并把她带走了
- Found her here. - And probably took her.
-我们还有机会  -贝奥武夫
- There's a chance. - Beowulf.
-解决了他们  -哇 哇 我
- Finish them. - Oi, oi, me?
我和他不熟
I hardly know him.
赫罗斯加会为你感到骄傲
Hrothgar would be proud
让别人来替你杀生
Getting others to do your killing for you.
你只跟我们一起住了一年  你对我父亲又了解什么
One year you lived with us. What do you know of my father?
那就来杀我吧  我都不会挑起一场打斗
Come on, then. I won't even put up a fight.
你以为我有那么怕你么
Or do I scare you that much?
如果这是你想要的死法
If that's how you want it.
他有刀
He's got a knife!
如果你们拿着武器再靠近我一点 他就会死
Before you get close enough to use those, he'll be dead.
动手吧
Do it!
-愤怒让你成为一个男人 -我已经不是你认识的那个小男孩了
- Anger makes a man of you.  - I'm not the boy you knew.
不是么
No?
你们想救他吗 来呀
You want him? Be my guest.
然后回去向他母亲解释发生了什么
Then go and explain to his mother what happened.
我们走
Let's go!
快点
Come on!
别告诉我你是为了这个女孩
Tell me this isn't about the girl.
不只是她  我答应替拜仁报仇的
Not just her. I pledged to avenge Bayen.
他都死了  还有什么意义呢
He's dead. What's it matter?
这有更多的脚印 而且更深
More tracks. Deeper.
野兽把她带走了
It's carrying her.
朝这个方向
This way.
人们是如何让巨兽建造如此雄伟的建筑的
How did men drive giants from these lands?
在我到来之前
Before my time.
我听说巨兽吃婴儿
I heard giants ate human babies.
-女人们编造的  -你不害怕吗
- Wives' tales.  - You're not scared?
那是什么
What was that?
来
Come on.
你闻到了吗
Do you smell that?
别动
Don't move.
爱尔维纳
Elvina!
嘿 嘿 这边
Hey! Hey!
小心
Look out!
啊
Agh!
呀啊
Yaaagh!
他怎么样了
How is he?!
我猜明天才能知道了
Doubt I'll see morning.
他会活下来的
He'll live.
利拉 我的寡妇
Lila? My widow.
你的丈夫相信 每一片乌云后面都有一片更黑暗的
Your husband believes every cloud has a darker one behind it.
闭上嘴你会怀孕吗
There's nothing more you can do here.
给你 能做到吗
There. Can you?
-你要去哪  -拜仁的尸体得收拾好
- Where are you going?  - Bayen's body must be prepared.
他死了 那我呢
He's dead. What about me?
奥 疼
Aw.
这是从杀死拜仁的泥巴种身上砍下来的
Cut from the mud-born that killed Bayen.
不是我看到过的那些身上的
Not from any I've seen.
在它来这之前 这野兽在北方路上屠杀了很多佃农
Before it came here, the beast had been slaughtering crofters on the Northern Road.
很好的故事 但是什么都证明不了
A pretty story. But it proves nothing.
贝奥武夫救了爱尔维纳的命 回到了这里
Beowulf saved Elvina's life and returned here.
这倒能说明点什么
That proves something.
只能证明他喜欢她
Only that he wants her.
你应该好好看看赫罗斯加的尸体
You may look upon Hrothgar's body.
然后请你离开
Then you will go.
本来应该是我救你的
It should've been me that saved you.
你已经救过我了 很多次
You already have. Many times.
我本来会把那野兽的脑袋砍下来
I'd have cut the beast's head off.
我很庆幸不是你砍的
Then I'm glad it wasn't you.
今晚见
See you tonight?
你找到玫瑰水了吗
Did you find the rosewater?
我来帮你
Let me help.
这是什么
What is it?
担心我会偷东西
Worried I might steal something?
如果你偷了我会知道的
If you did, I'd know.
在这座房子里 对于我来说没有任何秘密
There are no secrets from me within this hall.
贝奥武夫
Beowulf.
这里一直会是你的家 贝奥武夫
This hall will always be your home, Beowulf.
史林是你同父异母的哥哥
Slean is your half-brother.
你是我的血脉
You're all my blood.
我的儿子
My son.
别人都不知道
Nobody else knows.
你不属于这里
You don't belong here.
从来都不属于
Never did.
鹿厅需要你
'Heorot will need you.'
你的兄弟也会需要你
Your brother will need you.
而你会来的
'And you will come.'
-你现在要干什么  -把我开始的事情做个了结
- What will you do now?  - Finish what I started.
-杀死泥巴种  -那不是杀死拜仁的野兽
- Kill the mud-born.  - It wasn't the beast that killed Bayen.
-你怎么知道的  -伤口不是野兽造成的 他是被刺死的
- How do you know?   - The wound wasn't inflicted by a beast. He was stabbed.
-拜仁在这里有敌人吗  -他是赫罗斯加的总管
- Bayen had enemies here?  - He was Hrothgar's reeve.
也是我的 所有鹿厅的军队都是他的
Mine, too. All of Heorot's enemies were his.
他有很多敌人
And there are many.
即使是在和平年代
Even in a time of peace.
好吧 不管是谁 我会找到他们
Well, whoever it was, I'll find them...
杀了他们
and kill them.
变脸怪
It's a skin-shifter!
人们害怕他们比害怕泥巴种还多
People fear skin-shifters more than other mud-born
因为它们可以生活在我们之中而不被发现
Because they can live amongst us undetected.
如果被发现了 就会发生恐慌
If word gets out, there will be panic.
-你能找到然后杀了吗  -如果它还在的话
- Can you find the thing and kill it?  - If it's still here.
十五年来我都是一个会走会说的死人
I've been a walking, talking dead man for 15 years.
-你怎么在这  -杀人的是泥巴种
- Why are you here? - The killer was mud-born.
你不会以为是我吧
You can't think it's me.